# J. Jared Watson

PHONE 512 721 8658

EMAIL jjaredwatson@gmail.com

LINKEDIN

linkedin.com/in/jjaredwatson



## PORTFOLIO HIGHLIGHTS

**TacOMG** — A web application where a user is authenticated with Facebook credentials, and can create, post, and view their taco and other users' tacos in the gallery. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, and MongoDB.

tacomg.herokuapp.com/

**Drone DB** — A web application for people who are new to First Person View (FPV) Drone Racing. The app walks the user through the parts they will need to build a drone of their very own, with links to buy individual parts. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Materialize, React, Express, Node.js, and MongoDB.

dronedatabase.herokuapp.com/

### **EXPERIENCE**

# General Assembly / Austin, TX / April - July 2017

Web Development Immersive — Student

A full-stack web development program in a hands-on, 12 week immersive course.

# Olive & June / Austin, TX / January 2017 - April 2017

Event Staff, Server

I created a comfortable but elevated dining experience and consulted customers as they navigated the menu and suggested wine and beverage pairings. I contributed to a boost in overall sales, leading to the restaurant's most profitable winter quarter in 5 years.

# Progressive Insurance / Austin, TX / July 2016 - December 2016

Commercial Lines Service Specialist

I advised agents and customers on commercial insurance policies, and authored and expedited specialized documents, like state and federal filings, which decreased the amount of time customer's were out of compliance with local and national Department of Transportation requirements, thereby saving them time and money.

## Olivia / Austin, TX / 2013 - 2016

General Manager, Assistent Manager, Bar Tender

I overhauled our cocktail program and reduced waste by using fresh juices, making our own mixes from scratch, and by focusing on classic craft cocktails, while achieving the lowest liquor costs in years. I coordinated multiple large budget private events and oversaw their success. I hired and trained new employees and refocused my team on elevating the customer's experience.

## PROFILE

I am a highly adaptable web developer with a creative focus and intuitive nature. I enjoy collaborating with teams to produce meaningful work in an environment that encourages continual growth. I contribute an empathetic eye and valuable customer service experience to compliment any organization.

#### SKILLS

HTML Python **CSS Express** Bootstrap Node.js Materialize MongoDB JavaScript Git **j**Query Sketch React Affinity Designer Angular.js Affinity Photo

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Memphis

B.A. in English

Studied persuasive and creative writing, and literary criticism.

SEE MORE

jjaredwatson.com